forescout.com 2019-12-10

# Privacy Policy - Forescout

**Effective Date**

_August 13, 2019_

**Overview**

Forescout Technologies, Inc., including its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “ **Forescout** ,” “ **we** ,” or “ **us** ”) respects the privacy of our customers, business partners, event attendees, job applicants, and visitors to Forescout websites (“ **Sites** ”). We recognize the need for appropriate protections and management of personal information that is shared with and provided to Forescout. Forescout has developed this Privacy Policy to assist you to understand what personal information Forescout collects and how that personal information is used. It also describes your choices regarding the use, access and correction of your personal information. This Privacy Policy applies to Sites operated by Forescout such as www.forescout.com and other webpages in which we post and directly link to this policy.

**What personal information does Forescout collect?**

On Forescout Sites, you can:

  * Request information;
  * Obtain marketing or support materials;
  * Gather product information;
  * Register Forescout products and services;
  * Register for events; or
  * Apply for jobs at Forescout.

Forescout may collect personal information such as name, address, telephone number, email address, user ID and passwords, billing and transaction or other financial information, and contact preferences. Additionally, Forescout may collect information about your interactions and experiences on Forescout Sites, such as the pages you visit, content you view and frequency you come to Forescout Sites.

**Personal Information Supplementation**

In addition, Forescout may receive information about you from other sources, including publicly available databases or third parties from whom we have purchased data, and combine this data with information we already have about you. Forescout can use this information to update, expand and analyze our records, identify new customers, and tailor our advertising and promotions to provide products and services that may be of interest to you. If you provide us personal information about others, or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.

**Passive Collection**

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically. This information may include Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site.

**Cookies and Tracking Technologies**

Forescout, like many websites, uses cookies or similar technologies to collect additional website usage data and to improve our Sites. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer or device by websites that you visit or certain HTML formatted emails you open. The cookie will allow Forescout to remember information about you, your browsing activities, and your preferences until you either disable the cookie or exit the current browser. You can control the use of cookies at the [individual browser level,](http://www.whatarecookies.com/delete.asp) but if you choose to disable cookies, this may limit your use of certain features or functions on our Sites or products and services.

**How does Forescout use Personal information?**

Forescout uses the personal information we collect to provide customers, business partners and website visitors with information, special offerings, alerts and services and to help Forescout better understand your needs and interests. Specifically, Forescout may use the personal information to help you with our products and services including but not limited to ongoing service and support, to communicate with you, to provide you information about Forescout that you have requested, and to improve the performance of our websites and overall visitor experience. If you do not provide Forescout with your personal information, we may be unable to complete these functions. Occasionally we may use your information to contact you to complete surveys that we use for marketing and quality assurance purposes.

**Does Forescout share the personal information?**

Forescout contracts with third party service providers and suppliers (including distributors and resellers) to deliver certain products and services and customer solutions. Forescout may share personal information with its service providers and suppliers to the extent needed to deliver Forescout products and services or respond to requests for information on products or services or otherwise support your business needs. We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent. Forescout does not sell, rent or trade personal information it has collected.

We may use the information we collect to carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including without limitation, our Sites’ Terms of Use.

We may use the information to notify you about changes to our Sites or obtain any required consent.

We may use the information for industry analysis, benchmarking, analytics, marketing and other business purposes, including tracking your behavior as you engage with our Sites to determine how we can improve our service or whether you might be interested in our products and services.

In certain situations, Forescout may be required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or other law enforcement requirements.

Forescout may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

If Forescout is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal information held in our possession may be among the assets transfer to the buyer or acquirer.

**Marketing Communications**

We understand that subsequent contact can be an inconvenience. Whenever possible and on direct communications Forescout offers instructions on how to unsubscribe or limit future communications. These contact options include the acceptance or removal of subsequent emails and calls directly from Forescout, as well as your permission to receive information from Forescout. Please submit your request to our [Data Subject Request Web Portal](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/1efa5a15-c4d9-477e-b36d-f853f46257b1) so that we may apply commercially reasonable effort to eliminate further contact. To opt out of communications with our partners that you have provided your personal information, please contact them directly.

**Third-Party Websites**

We may use third party companies and individuals to provide services for the Sites (e.g. without limitation, display advertising on our Site or to manage our advertising on other sites, web analytics, conduct marketing activity on our behalf, and improve the Site features. Such third parties may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. Forescout does not exercise control over third party websites and this Privacy Policy only addresses Forescout’s use and disclosure of personal information we collect from you through use of our Sites. There are different ways you can prevent tracking of your online activity, including but not limited to setting a preference in your browser that can alert websites you visit to not collect information about you (‘Do-Not-Track’ or DNT signal). Additionally, if you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) [or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)]. Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

**E-mail or Newsletter Preferences**

You may sign up to receive email or newsletter or other communications from us. If you would like to discontinue receiving this information, you may update your email preferences by using the “Unsubscribe” link found in emails we send to you or at your member profile on our website or submitting your request to our [Data Subject Request Web Portal](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/1efa5a15-c4d9-477e-b36d-f853f46257b1).

**Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. We use appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect your personal information from misuse, unauthorized or unlawful access or disclosure, loss, damage or destruction including but not limited to physical access controls, encryption, and Internet firewalls. Forescout personnel and third parties who may have access to personal information are required to keep that information confidential. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, submit your request to our [Data Subject Request Web Portal](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/1efa5a15-c4d9-477e-b36d-f853f46257b1).

We may retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. If it is not possible to delete your information (for example, because your information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely protect your information and isolate it from any production use until deletion is possible.

**Access and Correction**

Upon request Forescout will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by logging into your account or submitting your request to our [Data Subject Request Web Portal](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/1efa5a15-c4d9-477e-b36d-f853f46257b1). We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

If you reside in the European Economic Area (EEA), you may have the right to exercise certain privacy rights available under applicable laws. 

  * Right not to provide consent or withdraw consent at any time.
  * Right to access the personal information we hold about you
  * Right of erasure if holding the personal information is no longer necessary for the purpose it was originally collected
  * Right to correct any inaccurate or incomplete personal information
  * Right to restrict processing where you believe that the personal information we hold about you is not accurate or lawfully held

If you would like to exercise any of the above rights, please submit your request to our [Data Subject Request Web Portal](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/1efa5a15-c4d9-477e-b36d-f853f46257b1). Forescout will process your request in accordance with applicable data protection law. To protect your privacy and security, we may take steps to verify your identity before complying. In certain circumstances, such as when Forescout process data on behalf of a third party, Forescout has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who  
seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should first direct their query to the relevant Forescout’s customer or client (the data controller), as applicable.

If you reside in the EEA, we will process your personal information pursuant to a legal basis as provided in the applicable data privacy laws (such as the General Data Protection Regulation). If we need to transfer your personal information outside of the EEA, we will transfer it to a territory that provides an adequate level of protection for personal information as determined by the European Commission (EC) or implement appropriate safeguards to protect our personal information such as the use of the Standard Contractual Clauses or another lawful transfer mechanism approved by the EC.

**Children**

Our Sites and business are not focused on, nor do we knowingly collect information from children under the age of 16.

**EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield**

Forescout participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. We are committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on the applicable Privacy Shield Framework. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and to view our certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List at [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/) _._

Forescout is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the applicable Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Forescout complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, Forescout is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>, you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

Forescout may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We will obtain your consent if and where required by applicable law. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

You will see when this Privacy Policy was last updated by checking the “Effective Date” displayed at the top of this Privacy Policy.

**How can I get more information about Forescout’s Privacy Policy?**

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy or believe that Forescout has not met its obligations as provided in this Privacy Policy, you may submit a complaint in writing to Forescout’s General Counsel, 190 West Tasman Drive, San Jose, California, 95134, USA or submit your request to our [Data Subject Request Web Portal](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/1efa5a15-c4d9-477e-b36d-f853f46257b1). Moreover, if you have an unresolved privacy concern that you feel Forescout has not adequately addressed, please contact our third-party dispute resolution provider at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request> or appropriate data protection authority. At any time, you may reach out to Forescout’s Privacy Team with any questions or concerns at [privacy@forescout.com](mailto:privacy@forescout.com).

  *[IP]: Internet Protocol
